baisidirect.com 2006-08-11

# Bank Security Features: Banking Privacy Policies from Bank of America

| | | | | | | |   
---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---  
| 

Overview

|   
|   
|   
|   
|   
|   
|   
|   
 | |   
---  
| |  |   
---  
  
## Set Your Online Banking Security Preferences  
  
You may choose to opt out of any or all of the following:  
  
  * Bank of America marketing offers
  * Sharing your information among Bank of America companies
  * Sharing your information with third parties

Set your preferences  
  
Summary of the Online Practices Privacy Policy  
---  
  
The Online Practices Privacy Policy explains how we may collect information from you online when you visit a Bank of America Web site. 

The Online Practices Privacy Policy, effective as of July 1, 2006, is for general guidance and subject to change. Please review periodically.

Customer information means personally identifiable information about a consumer or a consumer's current or former customer relationship with Bank of America.

Browsing our site  
  
You can browse our sites anonymously by choosing not to provide us with any personally identifiable information, such as your name or e-mail address, during your visits to our sites. When you browse this way, we won't be able to link your online activity with the accounts you have with us. 

Browsing anonymously after you've identified yourself involves setting your browser to disable cookies and similar files or by deleting the cookies and similar files that you have accepted from us. To do this, you'll need to follow your browser's instructions for disabling cookies or deleting cookies. Please note that the use of certain online products, such as Online Banking, do require the acceptance of cookies or similar files.

Cookies and Similar Files  
  
In all cases, cookies and similar files that we place on your computer do not contain any personal information unless encrypted, and we never use cookies or other files to track your use of other web sites. We may place cookies or similar files on your hard drive for security purposes, to facilitate site navigation, and to personalize your experience while visiting our site. Our cookies do not identify you as an individual or by account number. 

If you do not accept these cookies or similar files, you may experience some inconvenience in your use of some online products. For example, for Online Banking we will not be able to recognize your computer and you will need to answer a challenge question each time you log on.

Cookies are pieces of information stored directly on the computer you are using. Bank of America uses cookies in two ways:

  * Web Browsing Cookies. Cookies used for Web Browsing can contain a variety of information, such as a simple count of how often you visit a Web site or information that allows customization of a Web site for your use. Bank of America uses cookies to display information more effectively to you and to gather data about the usage of our Web site.  
Cookies allow us to collect technical and navigational information such as browser type, time spent on our site, and the pages visited. They do not contain or capture customer specific data. We may also use cookies in online advertising to track consumer responses to advertisement. This provides us the capability to monitor the use of our site so we can continually improve the design and functionality to better serve you. 

  * Online Banking. Bank of America uses cookies during your Online Banking Session. For example, to identify the state you are banking in so that we do not ask you to enter your state information more than once. Cookies are also used for security purposes in conjunction with our SiteKey service to recognize your computer. Any time a cookie is used, personal information is encrypted and used solely to support your Online Banking activity.

  * Similar Files. Some web sites use technologies similar to cookies to store information. For example, Bank of America also uses files called Flash Objects in connection with Online Banking. This is used to help assure security as part of our SiteKey service. As with cookies, we never store personal information unless encrypted, and we never use to track your use of other web sites.

Collecting information  
  
When you visit our Web site, we may collect the following information in order to service your accounts, save you time and money, and better respond to your needs: 

  * Application information. Information that you provide to us online in applications and other forms. Examples include your assets, income and debt.

  * Identification Information. Information that identifies you such as name, address, telephone number and Social Security number.

  * Transaction and experience information. Information about your online transactions and account experience, as well as information about our online communications with you. Examples include your online bill payments and your activity on the Web site, such as collecting information on product information reviewed.

How we may share information  
  
Bank of America may share Customer Information we collect from you online with our family of companies and with companies that work for us. All nonaffiliated companies that act on our behalf and receive Customer Information from us are contractually obligated to keep the information we provide to them confidential and to use the Customer Information we share only to provide the services we ask them to perform. These companies may include financial service providers such as payment processing companies, and nonfinancial companies such as check printing and data processing companies. 

We also may disclose Customer Information we collect about you online to credit bureaus and similar organizations and when required or permitted by law. For example, Customer Information may be disclosed in connection with a subpoena or similar legal process, fraud prevention or investigation, risk management and security, and the recording of deeds of trust and mortgages in public records. 

Customer Information may also be disclosed to companies that process your requests for products or services or in connection with the sale of your account to another financial institution. We also may share Customer Information outside Bank of America companies when we have your consent, such as when you request a specific insurance rate quote from a third party insurer. 

For customers with credit cards and Sponsored Accounts we may share Identification Information, Transaction and Experience Information, as well as Other General Information we collect about each of your Bank of America or MBNA credit card accounts and Sponsored Accounts, with selected third parties. Examples of these organizations include colleges, sporting teams, retailers and other affinity organizations such as charities. 

For more information on how Bank of America shares your information, please refer to the Bank of America Privacy Policy for Consumers. 

Making sure information is accurate  
  
Keeping your account information accurate and up to date is very important. If your account information is incomplete, inaccurate or not current, please call or write to us at the telephone number or appropriate address for such changes listed on your account statement, bank records or other account materials. 

Changes to the Online Practices Privacy Policy  
  
If we make changes to the Online Practices Privacy Policy or make any material changes to our online services, we will revise the Online Practices Privacy Policy to reflect such changes and revise the policy's effective date.  
  
View the full Online Practices Privacy Policy.  
|
